

Faisal Ahmed

(571) 409-8514 | E: mishu_dc@yahoo.com. Status: Permanent Resident 4200 CONALLY ST, APT 101, Annandale, VA 22003

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full stack software developer with 7+ years of experience in web development using Asp.net MVC, Asp.net Web API, Entity Framework, ReactJs and

Angular. 4+ years of experience in Web automation using Selenium WebDriver and Cucumber. Currently looking for a full-time position as a full stack developer in a challenging environment to utilize my skill and knowledge to the best of my abilities and contribute positively to my personal growth as well as growth of the organization.

SKILLS

- C#
- Asp.net MVC
- Asp.net Web API
- Entity Framework
- nHybernet
- jQuery
- ReactJs

- Angular
- Java
- Selenium WebDriver
- Cucumber
- Visual Studio
- Visual Studio Code
- Git

WORK HISTORY

QA ENGINEER

01/2015 to CURRENT

DrFirst, Inc | Rockville, MD

- Projects: Electronic Prior Authorization, Patient Real Time Benefit Inquiry,
 Gaps in Care, Care Cost Estimator etc.
- Primary role is to automate web interfaces using Selenium
 WebDriver and Cucumber, Api automation using Java, JMeter, Postman,
 Java and verify user acceptance criteria.
- Worked in a ReactJs web portal as a software developer.
- Took the lead role in multiple UATs with Humana, Argus, United Health Group on behalf of DrFirst.
- Played the role of an acting application delivery manager for a short period of time.
- Participated in the myBenefitCheck project for Humana which was reported in Yahoo Finance in 2015

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

04/2011 to 09/2014

XpertLab BD Ltd. | Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Projects: E-Commerce System, Mobile based Order Capturing System,
 Distribution Management System etc.
- Collaborate with developers, QA, product owner and scrum master to assess requirements, prioritize needs and produce high quality product.
- Mobile based Order Capturing System helped one renounced pharmaceutical company to double the number of invoices on month opening.

 Technology used: C#.net, Asp.Net MVC, Web Api, nHybernet, SQL Server.

PROGRAMMER ANALYST

12/2006 to 03/2010

Computer Ease Ltd. | Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Projects: Humane Resource Management, Payroll Management System, Distribution Management System.
- Participated in different steps of SDLC.
- Designed and developed application based on requirements using C#.net, Asp.Net, SQL Server, SOAP Services, J2ME.
- Migrated legacy Visual Basic project To C#.net.

EDUCATION ()

Master of Science | Computer Science United International University, Dhaka

2013

2006

Bachelor of Science | Computer Science and Engineering
Ahsanullah University of Science and Technology, Dhaka

CERTIFICATIONS

Exam 483: Programming in C#